The series is one of the core data structures in pandas.
系列(Series)是Pandas中的核心數據結構之一。
You think of it a cross between a list and a dictionary.
你可以想像一下相交於列表(list)和字典(dictionary)之間。
The items are all stored in an order and
這些項目都按照順序儲存，
there's labels with which you can retrieve them.
並且有標籤可以從中檢索。
An easy way to visualize this is two columns of data.
一個簡單的方法去想象，它是兩列數據。
The first is the special index, a lot like the dictionary keys.
第一欄是特殊的索引，很像字典dictionary的key。
While the second is your actual data.
而第二欄則是你真實的數據。
It's important to note that the data column has a label of its own and
重要的是注意資料欄位也有自己的標籤
can be retrieved using the .name attribute.
可以透過 .name 來取得
This is different than with dictionaries and
這與dictionary不同，
is useful when it comes to merging multiple columns of data.
在合併多列數據時很有用。
And we'll talk about that later on in the course.
我們稍後再談談。
As you might expect, you can create a series by passing in a list of values.
你可能會預期，可以透過傳遞一個 list 的值來新創一個 Series
When you do this, Pandas automatically assigns an index starting with zero and
當你這麼做時， Pandas 會自動從零開始分配索引
sets the name of the series to None.
並將該series的名稱設置為“None”。
Let's see an example of this.
我們來看個例子
First, I'll start off by importing the pandas library as pd,
首先，我輸入pandas程式庫，將它設定為pd，
then let's take a look at the series object.
讓我們看一下 Series 物件
Here you could see the documentation indicates that you can pass in some data,
從文件中可以看出 你可以傳入一些資料
an index and a name.
索引和名稱
The data can be anything, that's array-like, like a list.
資料可以是任何東西，類似陣列(array)，像list一樣。
So let's give that a try.
讓我們來試一試。
We'll just make a list of the three of my favorite animals, a tiger,
我會用三個我喜歡的動物來建立串列
a bear and a moose.
獅子，熊和麋鹿
We'll see here that the pandas has automatically identified the type of
我們看到這裡pandas自動的識別了類型
the data being held in the list, in this case we passed in a list of strings and
在list中包含的數據，在這裡我們傳入string列表，
panda set the type to object.
pandas將這類型設定為object。
We don't have to use strings.
我們不一定要使用strings。
If we passed in a list of whole numbers, for instance,
如果我們傳入整數列表，例如，
we could see that panda sets the type to n 64.
可以看見Pandas設定類型為int64。
Underneath panda stores series values in a typed array using the Numpy library.
在Pandas內部儲存series的值，使用NumPy程式庫的類型陣列(typed array)。
This offers significant speed-up when processing data versus traditional
在處理數據時這提供顯著的加速，比較於傳統
python lists.
Python的list
There's some other typing details that exist for
還有一些其他有關類型的細節存在，
performance that are important to know.
對於其性能的了解很重要。
The most important is how Numpy and thus pandas handle missing data.
最重要的是 NumPy 和 Pandas 如何處理遺失的資料
In Python, we have the none type to indicate a lack of data.
在Python中，我們有none type以表示資料缺失。
But what do we do if we want to have a typed list like we do in
但是我們該怎麼做，如果我們想要有一個類型的list，像我們在
the series object?
series object?
Underneath, pandas does some type conversion.
在內部，pandas會執行一些類型轉換。
If we create a list of strings and we have one element, a None type,
如果我們創建一個list的strings，而我們有一個元素是None類型，
pandas inserts it as a None and uses the type object for the underlying array.
pandas將它作為None，並使用object的類型在內部陣列。
If we create a list of numbers, integers or floats, and put in the None type,
如果我們創建一個數字，整數或浮點的列表，並放入None類型，
pandas automatically converts this to a special floating point value designated as
Pandas會自動將其轉換為特殊浮點值，指定為NaN，
NAN, which stands for not a number.
代表它不是一個數字。
For those who might not have done scientific computing in Python before,
對於那些沒有用過Python科學計算的人，
this is a pretty important point.
這是一個很重要的一點。
NAN is not none and when we try the equality test, it's false.
NaN不是None，當我們嘗試相等測試時，它是偽的
It turns out that you actually can't do an equality test of NAN to itself.
原來你還不能做Nan本身的相等測試。
When you do, the answer is always false.
當你這樣做時，答案總是錯誤的。
You need to use special functions to test for
你需要使用特殊功能來測試
the presence of not a number, such as the Numpy library is NAN.
'不是一個數字'的存在，例如numpy程式庫中的isnan。
We'll come back to this later in the assignment, but
我們稍後將在作業中再回來這，
keep in mind when you see NAN, it's meaning is similar to none, but
請記住，當你看到Nan，它意思類似于none，但
it's a numeric value and it's treated differently for efficiency reasons.
它是一個數值，它的區別對待是因為效率的原因。
Let's talk more about how pandas' series can be created.
讓我們來談談如何可以創造出pandas的series。
While my list of animals might be a common way to create some play data,
雖然我的動物列表可能是創建一些玩的數據的常用方法，
often you have label data that you want to manipulate.
但通常你需標籤的數據來操作。
A series can be created from dictionary data.
series可以從dictionary數據來創建。
If you do this, the index is automatically assigned to the keys of the dictionary
如果這樣做，你提供的dictionary的keys將自動指派成索引(index)
that you provided and not just incrementing integers.
，而不僅僅是遞增整數的index。
Here's an example using some data from Wikipedia on official national sports.
這裡有一個使用維基百科的官方全國運動的數據的例子。
When we create the series, we see that,
當我們創建的series時，我們看到，
since it was string data, panda set the data type of the series to object.
因為它是string數據，pandas將一系列的數據類型設置為object。
We set the list of the countries as the value of the series and
我們將國家列表設置為series的value，
that the index values can be set to the keys from our dictionary.
並將index的value設置為我們的dictionary中的keys。
Once the series has been created,
series創建完成後，
we can get the index object using the index attribute.
我們可以使用index屬性獲取index對象。
You could also separate your index creation from the data by passing in
你也可以將index的創建與數據分離，通過
the index as a list explicitly to the series.
將index作為列表，明確地傳遞給series。
So what happens if your list of values in the index
那麼如果index中的值列表
object are not aligned with the keys in your dictionary for creating the series?
與dictionary中用於創建該系列的keys不對齊，會發生什麼？
Well, pandas overrides the automatic creation to favor only and
在這種情況下，pandas會覆蓋自動創建index值，僅只偏用
all of the indices values that you provided.
你提供的所有的index值。
So it will ignore it from your dictionary, all keys, which are not in your index, and
它會忽略你的dictionary中所有的keys，當keys不在你的index中，而且
pandas will add non type or NAN values for any index value you provide,
pandas將添加non類型或NaN值，在你提供的任何index值，
which is not in your dictionary key list.
而不存在你的dictionary的key列表中。
In this example, we pass in a dictionary of four items but
在這個例子中，我們傳遞一個四個項目的dictionary，
only two are preserved in the series object because of the index list.
由於index列表，只有兩個保留在series object。
We see that hockey has been added but since it's also in the index list,
我們看到曲棍球已被添加，但是由於它也在index列表中，
it has no value associated with it.
它沒有相關的值。
So that's how we create a series.
這就是我們如何創建series。
In the next class, we'll dig deeper and look at how we get data out of the series.
在下一課中，我們將深入研究如何從series中獲取數據。